<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="Joomla! - Open Source Content Management" -->
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/media/flickrsuite/css/widget.min.css" type="text/css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/plugins/system/jce/css/content.css?fa74ed6d29bc94cadf25b557da065e6d" type="text/css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>News</title>
		<description><![CDATA[Official website of the International Federation of Sport Climbing. Find events calendar, all past and future results, rankings, IFSC news, photos, videos.]]></description>
		<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 22:17:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Joomla! - Open Source Content Management</generator>
		<atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news?format=feed&amp;type=rss"/>
		<language>en-gb</language>
		<item>
			<title>SCHALCK TAKES GOLD; VAN DUYSEN CLAIMS BELGIUM'S FIRST EVER IFSC WORLD CUP MEDAL</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/921-schalck-takes-gold-van-duysen-claims-belgium-s-first-ever-ifsc-world-cup-medal</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/921-schalck-takes-gold-van-duysen-claims-belgium-s-first-ever-ifsc-world-cup-medal</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230423_IFSC_News_Schalck_takes_gold_Van_Duysen_claims_Belgiums_first_ever_World_Cup_medalPREV.jpg" /></p><p>France’s Mejdi Schalck took one of two French medals at the IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023 as Belgian teenager Hannes Van Duysen made history with a first ever World Cup medal for the nation.</p>

<p>Schalck was appearing in his 11<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;IFSC World Cup and claimed his second gold medal at the&nbsp;Esforta Arena Hachioji.</p>
<p>The Frenchman took two finals tops, the only climber to do so, and finished ahead of history maker Van Duysen and teammate Paul Jenft who took bronze.</p>
<p>Talking of his win Schalck said: <em>“I’m very happy with the gold as it’s been a big goal I have been training for over winter. I wanted to win a second medal to show myself I could do it.”</em></p>
<p>With compatriot Jenft on the podium, Schalck appreciates the strong training position they are in together: <em>“We have trained together for about five or six years and the ‘rivalry’ pushes us on to the top. We push each other and it is a really good rivalry for the both of us.”</em></p>
<p>Despite the chance to make history, Van Duysen could have felt the weight of pressure on him, especially in only his fifth appearance at an IFSC World Cup, but instead he used the excitement to his advantage: <em>“It’s the first time for Belgium to get a medal so that’s pretty cool. It’s amazing to be here and every round was incredible for me.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>“I was excited to be in the semi-final and then I didn’t have any pressure, so I just climbed how I wanted to and made the final. Then to end up on the podium is very crazy.”</em></p>
<p>Only&nbsp;the second Belgian to make an IFSC Boulder World Cup final, Van Duysen reflected on a debut year in 2022 to focus and progress through the winter, and it paid off: <em>“I competed in a few World Cups last year, but I made a lot of silly mistakes, so it didn’t go that well.</em></p>
<p><em>“My positioning, the slabs weren’t really that good, but my training during the winter went really well and I found a better way to move on the boulders and I think this was the key to break through in a senior event.”</em></p>
<p>France’s Paul Jenft produced a personal best result to take the bronze medal and join his training partner Schalck on the podium: <em>“It’s a bit of a relief because all the finals I have done I always end up in fourth, so it’s really cool to make the podium after three finals and three fourth places.”</em></p>
<p>Joking about gold medallist Schalck, Jenft said: <em>“I’m happy but I’m also frustrated because Mejdi always beats me. But he pushes me to be stronger because he’s my friend and we train really well together.”</em></p>
<p>Home nation climbers&nbsp;Fujii Kokoro&nbsp;finished fourth and debutant Anraku Sorato finished just behind in fifth. South Korea’s Chon Jongwon was sixth.</p>
<p>The&nbsp;IFSC World Cup&nbsp;will now move on to Seoul, South Korea&nbsp;from 28-30 April with the Boulder and Speed disciplines.</p>
<p>Full men's Boulder results can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=da16a5b4ef&amp;e=ebc07658c0" data-ogsc="rgb(0, 0, 0)">here</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230423_IFSC_News_Schalck_takes_gold_Van_Duysen_claims_Belgiums_first_ever_World_Cup_medal.jpg" alt="230423 IFSC News Schalck takes gold Van Duysen claims Belgiums first ever World Cup medal" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Men's Boulder podium at IFSC World Cup&nbsp;Hachioji 2023 </span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC&nbsp;</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 11:58:07 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MENTAL STRENGTH HELPS FRANCE’S JENFT TOP SEMI-FINAL</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/920-mental-strength-helps-france-s-jenft-top-semi-final</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/920-mental-strength-helps-france-s-jenft-top-semi-final</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230423_IFSC_News_Mental_strength_helps_frances_jenft_top_qualification_PREV.jpg" /></p><p>Paul Jenft of France finished in pole position in the men’s Boulder semi-finals at the&nbsp;IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023&nbsp;as one of only two climbers to top two boulders.</p>

<p>South Korea’s Chon Jongwon was the other athlete to top two boulders and also goes through to the final.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Despite leading the way into the final six, Jenft wasn’t feeling in peak condition for the semi-finals:&nbsp;<em>“I’m really happy with my performance. It was a hard round and the boulders were really physical. I felt a little bit weak in that round, but my mind was really strong. I was able to get two tops and I was happy with that.”</em></p>
<p>Even as top of the leaderboard, Jenft didn’t have any explanation for his lack of strength:&nbsp;<em>“You train to be strong and some days it just doesn’t work, you just feel a bit weak. And today was one of those days.</em><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>“After the first two boulders I didn’t have any tops and I thought they were more my style. The last two weren’t so much, so I had to be mentally strong to do those last two. But I am happy to make it through to the final.”&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>Just behind Jenft and Jongwon in first and second, the hot new property in Japanese climbing, Anraku Sorato, again showed his potential by leading the home nation hunt for a medal qualifying in third.</p>
<p>There will be two French and two Japanese athletes in the final as Mejdi Schalck, qualifying in fourth position, joins compatriot Jenft and Fujii Kokoro, in sixth, joins young gun Sorato.</p>
<p>In August 2022 Sorato was picking up a bronze medal in the Youth A category of the Youth World Championships. At the same time Belgium’s Hannes Van Duysen was picking up Junior gold. They will now be fighting it out for IFSC World Cup medals with Van Duysen also through to the final in fifth position.</p>
<p>Full women's Boulder semi-final results can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/world-competition/calendar/?task=resultathletes&amp;event=1291&amp;result=3">here</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finals begin at the&nbsp;Esforta Arena Hachioji&nbsp;at 17:00 (UTC+9:00).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230423_IFSC_News_Mental_strength_helps_frances_jenft_top_qualification.jpg" alt="230423 IFSC News Mental strength helps frances jenft top qualification" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">France's Paul Jenft celebrates a top in the men's Boulder semi-finals</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Dimitris Tosidis / IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 05:00:54 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>USA’S RABOUTOU CLAIMS FIRST EVER IFSC BOULDER WORLD CUP GOLD</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/919-usa-s-raboutou-claims-first-ever-ifsc-boulder-world-cup-gold</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/919-usa-s-raboutou-claims-first-ever-ifsc-boulder-world-cup-gold</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230422_IFSC_News_Raboutou_claims_first_ever_IFSC_Boulder_World_Cup_gold_PREV.jpg" /></p><p>American Brooke Raboutou’s smile lit the&nbsp;Esforta Arena Hachioji today&nbsp;after claiming her first ever IFSC Boulder World Cup gold medal.</p>

<p>Raboutou was head and shoulders above her competition in Hachioji, Japan, gaining confidence every time she climbed. The USA climber topped three boulders and hit four zones in the final with her closest rival only managing a single top.</p>
<p>Germany’s Hannah Meul was that rival, and she claimed the silver ahead of the home nation favourite Matsufuji Anon who took bronze.</p>
<p>The final was contested by six athletes who had never won an IFSC Boulder World Cup so a new gold medallist was guaranteed. In fact, the last 17&nbsp;IFSC&nbsp;World&nbsp;Cup Boulder events&nbsp;have been won by&nbsp;either USA’s&nbsp;Natalia&nbsp;Grossman or Slovenia’s&nbsp;Janja&nbsp;Garnbret and you have to go back to IFSC World Cup Vail 2018 to find another winner when Alex Puccio of USA won gold.</p>
<p>In disbelief of her maiden gold, Raboutou said:&nbsp;<em>“It’s crazy. I feel a lot. It hasn’t really sunk. I knew I had one when I topped the last boulder, but even then, I was like ‘are you sure?’. Most of all I just feel thankful and really happy with my climbing today.”</em></p>
<p>Well known through the climbing community, Raboutou’s family are a big influence, and she becomes the second generation to claim a World Cup gold after mum Robyn Erbesfield-Raboutou:&nbsp;<em>“I called my parents and they are very, very happy. My mum just told me she was really proud of me, but I feel that every day with them anyway.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p><em>“As much as winning a World Cup was a big dream for me, I had to thank my parents because they got me here and they get me up the wall.”</em></p>
<p>The only other athlete to top a finals Boulder, Meul, was excited not only for her podium finish, but what lies ahead in the coming months:&nbsp;<em>“It’s amazing. I’m super happy to start the season like this. It’s definitely the best start. I had the perfect mixture of being nervous, but also confident in my climbing and what I am capable of.”</em></p>
<p>Despite the happiness picking up a medal, there was also a touch of sadness and reflection as she celebrated the life of teammate Christoph Schweiger who dies recently in a road traffic accident:&nbsp;“This competition was the hardest emotionally. The most important thing in this competition was to carry my teammate Christoph Schweiger in my heart.&nbsp;</p>
<p>“He was supposed to be here to climb and show what he could do. So, it was important to enjoy this gift that we have to be here and climb. The love we have and all share for climbing is something that cannot die, so I wanted to chase that spirit for him. He gave me a lot of power in the end.”</p>
<p>Rounding out the podium was Anon who gave the cheering home crowd a greater opportunity to raise their voice when it was confirmed she would leave Hachioji with a World Cup bronze.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In fourth place was&nbsp;Ayala Kerem from Israel who secured her best ever IFSC World Cup Boulder finish. China’s Luo&nbsp;Zhilu&nbsp;finished in fifth with Mia Krampl of Slovenia in sixth.</p>
<p>IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023 will finish tomorrow (Sunday 23 April) with the men’s Boulder semi-final at 11:00 (UTC+9:00) and final at 17:00 (UTC+9:00).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230422_IFSC_News_Raboutou_claims_first_ever_IFSC_Boulder_World_Cup_gold.jpg" alt="230422 IFSC News Raboutou claims first ever IFSC Boulder World Cup gold" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Women's Boulder podium at IFSC World Cup</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hachioji 2023&nbsp;© Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 12:17:43 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MEUL LEADS THE WAY FOR HACHIOJI BOULDER FINAL</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/918-meul-leads-the-way-for-hachioji-boulder-final</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/918-meul-leads-the-way-for-hachioji-boulder-final</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230422_IFSC_News_Meul_leads_the_way_for_hachioji_boulder_finalsPREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">Germany’s Hannah Meul continued her strong finish to the 2022 season by leading the way into the IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023 Boulder finals.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">The German climber has been working hard all winter and is in Hachioji to prove to herself, and others, last year was not just a one-off: <em>“The hardest part about climbing is the expectations you put on yourself, but I also felt because of having a good year last year people expect more from me – it is a bit hard and you feel a bit of pressure but I actually enjoyed it.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“I enjoy being back in public and showing what I worked on all over winter. I really wanted to be back in competition, and it actually feels a bit like coming home and more fun. All the simulation competitions are great, but I felt much more pressure in them actually.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“Standing on the mat and looking up at the wall is where I feel at home. I’m so glad to be back, it’s so much fun.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Meul topped two boulders and hit four zones, the same as Luo Zhilu of China, who goes through in second, and Brooke Raboutou of USA who is third.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There is home nation interest in the final with&nbsp;Matsufuji Anon&nbsp;who goes through in fourth position, just ahead of Israel’s Ayala&nbsp;Kerem.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mia Krampl of Slovenia completes the final six finishing just ahead of Noa Shiran. Before Hachioji Shiran’s personal best was 45<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;position, so a strong and exciting start for the 2023 season for the Israeli climber.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some big names like Nonaka Miho, Natalia Grossman and Jessica Pilz miss out on finals in the first event of the season.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Full women's Boulder semi-final results can be found <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/world-competition/calendar/?task=resultathletes&amp;event=1291&amp;result=7">here</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Finals begin at the&nbsp;Esforta Arena Hachioji&nbsp;at 17:00 (UTC+9:00).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230422_IFSC_News_Meul_leads_the_way_for_hachioji_boulder_finals.jpg" alt="230422 IFSC News Meul leads the way for hachioji boulder finals" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Germany's Hannah Meul in semi-finals action</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo; Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 04:59:51 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>STRONG JAPANESE SEMI-FINAL PRESENCE AFTER HACHIOJI QUALIFICATION </title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/917-strong-japanese-semi-final-presence-after-hachioji-qualification</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/917-strong-japanese-semi-final-presence-after-hachioji-qualification</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230421_IFSC_News_qualification_gets_underway_in_HachiojiPREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">The IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023 got underway today with qualification in both the men’s and women’s Boulder.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>WOMEN'S QUALIFICATION</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Getting the event started was Japan’s Nonaka Miho and USA’s Natalia Grossman, who is on a run of five consecutive IFSC World Cup Boulder wins, for the women’s qualification.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">With 74 climbers competing in the women’s competition, the athletes were split into two groups – group A and group B. Because of a tie for tenth position in Group B, 21 athletes progressed through to the semi-finals which take place tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Climbers handle being the first on the mat for a competition differently, for 2022 IFSC World Cup Boulder Series champion Grossman, it’s not something she particularly enjoys:&nbsp;<em>“I never really like going first, it feels weird to be out on your own at the start, but I guess it’s fine.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Talking about her goals for the event, Grossman said:&nbsp;<em>“Just being out here and getting to compete again after a really long time.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>"I’ve been focusing a lot more on Lead the past couple of months, and so there’s always a little bit of sacrifice when you focus on one discipline more than the other, but it’s exciting to get to test myself again on some new boulders.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Both Miho and Grossman made it through to the semi-finals with the Japanese climber taking top spot alongside compatriot Matsufuji Anon and Grossman in fifth alongside another Japanese climber, Sekikawa Melody.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Israel’s Ayala Kerem and USA’s Brooke Raboutou move through&nbsp;to semi-finals in third which will feature eight home nation athletes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Full women's Boulder qualification results can be found <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/world-competition/calendar/?task=resultathletes&amp;event=1291&amp;result=7">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>MEN'S QUALIFICATION</strong></p>
<p>Ninety-six men competed in the Boulder qualification with the Japanese climbers dominating the top five across the two groups – group A and group B.</p>
<p>Narasaki Tomoa excelled in group B topping all five boulders and progressing in first position alongside South Korea’s Lee Dohyun who also managed to top all problems in group A.</p>
<p>Ogata Yoshiyuki was a little nervous before competing but settled down once he got on to the mat. The Japanese climber also topped all five of the Boulders in Group A and qualified for semi-finals in third.</p>
<p>Talking of the pressure of competing on home soil, Yoshiyuki said: <em>“I was nervous about climbing in Japan as I was the champion last year and there may be a little bit of pressure, but I’m quite happy now because I know my friends and family will come to support me on the final day.”</em></p>
<p>Yoshiyuki was also happy that his country opened the season saying: <em>“It’s fun. I think the walls in Japan are a little bit different to other places in the world so it’s good to have the first World Cup of the season here.”</em></p>
<p>Also progressing in third was teammate Fujii Kokoro with 16-year-old Anraku Sorato making it four in the top five for the Asian country.</p>
<p>European Boulder champion Nicolai Uznik of Austria also progressed to the semi-final which will take place on Sunday 23 April.</p>
<p>Full men's qualification results can be found&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/world-competition/calendar/?task=resultathletes&amp;event=1291&amp;result=3" data-ogsc="rgb(0, 0, 0)">here</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230421_IFSC_News_qualification_gets_underway_in_Hachioji.jpg" alt="230421 IFSC News qualification gets underway in Hachioji" width="800" height="534" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Great Britain's Erin McNeice in qualification action</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 05:28:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IFSC WORLD CUP HACHIOJI 2023: Q&amp;A WITH NOGUCHI AKIYO</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/916-ifsc-world-cup-hachioji-2023-q-a-with-noguchi-akiyo</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/916-ifsc-world-cup-hachioji-2023-q-a-with-noguchi-akiyo</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230421_IFSC_News_hachioji_qanda_with_noguchi_akiyoPREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">With the IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023 starting, we had a quick catch-up with someone who knows a thing or two about climbing, and climbing in Japan, Olympic bronze medallist&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=2253">Noguchi Akiyo</a>, for some thoughts on the event and her ones-to-watch.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>You stepped away from competing on the World Cup circuit last year, what did you do with your time?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Climbing is still a big part of my life.&nbsp;I&nbsp;hold climbing classes for children and adults as well as climbing events and competitions.&nbsp;In addition, I am spending a lot of time doing TV appearances and at events other than climbing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Did you follow the IFSC World Cup last year?&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I do TV commentary in Japan, and of course, I support the Japanese team, so I watch all the World Cup events, whether it's Lead, Boulder, or Speed, as much as possible.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Do you still have contact with the Japanese Climbing team?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some of the climbers come to practice at the gym in my parents' house, and I go to the domestic competitions and talk with members of the Japanese Climbing team there. I always watch Tomoa and Meichi (Narasaki) training as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>What are your memories from Hachioji?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I&nbsp;was&nbsp;second at the World Cup held for the first time in Hachioji in 2017. And then I won the 2018 World Cup. At the 2019 World Championships, I placed second in Boulder and second in the Combined, and that place secured me qualification for the Olympics. So, a lot of good memories for me from Hachioji.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>What advice would you give athletes competing, maybe for the first time in Hachioji?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Hachioji is a big city, so you can enjoy a good dinner after climbing – I’d recommend that. Also, I hear that the tickets for the event are sold out, so I think it's going to be a wonderful environment with a lot of spectators so try to enjoy the experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Who should we look out for in Hachioji, who are the ones-to-watch?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In the&nbsp;men's it has to be Sorato Anraku for me. He won the Boulder &amp; Lead&nbsp;Japan Cup the other day and I believe he is a 16-year-old who will challenge for World Cup medals this year. Expectations are high to see how well he can demonstrate his abilities in international competitions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The woman, well obviously it’s Japan's ace, Miho Nonaka.&nbsp;I'm sure she will be involved in the fight all year, right from the first event in Hachioji.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>What about the whole season, who are your ones-to-watch there?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For the men's event, I’m picking France's Méjdi Schalck.&nbsp;With Paris 2024 coming up, the young French ace will be under a little bit of pressure, but I’m sure he will give some great performances.　</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On the women's side, it might seem like a popular opinion, but I'm really looking forward to the return of Janja Garmbret of Slovenia. I often see her training on social media, and I really respect her for being strong every year. I want to see her back performing at the competitions soon.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Climbing starts in Hachioji, Japan, with the women’s Boulder qualification at 09:00 (UTC+9:00)&nbsp;before the men’s qualification at 16:30 (UTC+9:00)&nbsp;on Friday, 21 April.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230421_IFSC_News_hachioji_qanda_with_noguchiakiyo.jpg" alt="230421 IFSC News hachioji qanda with noguchiakiyo" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Noguchi Akiyo competes in the women's Combined final at Tokyo 2020</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Leo Zhukov/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 23:56:02 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>HACHIOJI SET TO HOST IFSC WORLD CUP SERIES 2023 OPENER</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/915-hachioji-set-to-host-ifsc-world-cup-series-2023-opener</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/915-hachioji-set-to-host-ifsc-world-cup-series-2023-opener</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230420_IFSC_News_-_Hachioji_set_to_host_IFSC_World_Cup_Series_2023_opener_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">The 2023 IFSC World Cup Series kicks off in Hachioji, Japan, this weekend as competitors from around the world compete for the first World Cup medals of the year.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Taking place from 21 to 23 April, 171 athletes&nbsp;– 95 male and 76 female – representing 40 countries and territories will battle it out in Boulder at the Esforta Arena Hachioji – the venue of the IFSC World Championships in 2019.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Looking through the <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/world-competition/calendar?task=starters&amp;event=1291">start list</a> of competitors, <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=1803">Natalia Grossman</a> of the USA immediately leaps from the page with a run of five consecutive wins in the 2022 Boulder World Cup competitions – only Slovenian Janja Garnbret beat the American last season at the opener in Meiringen, Switzerland.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Grossman is joined by a strong American contingent that includes young gun <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=13021">Anastasia Sanders</a>, the 2022 and 2021 Youth Worlds champion, and Olympian <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=1811">Brooke Raboutou</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Germany’s <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=3113">Hannah Meul</a> finished the 2022 Boulder season strongly with two Boulder silver medals in Brixen, Italy, and Innsbruck, Austria, and will hope the run of medals continues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While Grossman dominated the women’s Boulder podium last season, the men’s was totally different with six different gold medallists from the six competitions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Japan was well represented throughout the Boulder season with <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=2276">Narasaki Tomoa</a> and <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=2309">Ogata Yoshiyuki</a> both picking up a full set of gold, silver and bronze medals, and are part of a large Japanese contingent of 12 climbers in the men’s event.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">European Boulder champion <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=1256">Nicolai Uznik</a> of Austria, Olympic champion <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=811">Alberto&nbsp;Ginés López</a>&nbsp;of Spain, and Youth Worlds champion <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=373">Hannes Van Duysen</a> are all in Hachoiji to see if they can add to their titles and begin the year on a high.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">From athletes with plenty of World Cup experience under their belts, to some with none. While there is a host of new young climbers taking their first steps in World Cup competitions, Pilipinas Climbing have brought three World Cup newbies for the 2023 kick off.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=3830">Iman Mora</a>, 34, and <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=3834">John Joseph Veloria</a>, 30, make their World Cup debuts in the men’s Boulder with teammate <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/component/ifsc/?task=athlete.display&amp;id=3832">Nicole Liana Mora</a>, 32, making hers in the women’s – all proving age is just a number.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230420_IFSC_News_-_Hachioji_set_to_host_IFSC_World_Cup_Series_2023_opener.jpg" alt="230420 IFSC News Hachioji set to host IFSC World Cup Series 2023 opener" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Fujii Kokoro competes in the men's Boulder event at last year's IFSC World Cup Seoul in Seoul, South Korea</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 11:33:58 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>HIGHAM'S HIGHLIGHTS: IFSC WORLD CUP HACHIOJI 2023</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/914-higham-s-highlights-ifsc-world-cup-hachioji-2023</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/914-higham-s-highlights-ifsc-world-cup-hachioji-2023</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230419_IFSC_News_Highams_highlights_IFSC_World_Cup_Hachioji_2023PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">Throughout the 2023 season the IFSC will bring some interesting facts and figures ahead of our events, in association with statistician Paul Higham. The first set of stats is for the upcoming World Cup series opener in Hachioji, Japan from 21 – 23 April 2023 at the Esforta Arena Hachioji.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>HIGHLIGHTS</strong><br />&nbsp;<br />IFSC World Cup Hachioji will the&nbsp;387th Senior World Cup&nbsp;event&nbsp;and the&nbsp;145th Boulder World Cup&nbsp;competition for&nbsp;men and&nbsp;women.<br />&nbsp;<br />It will be the&nbsp;12th World Cup&nbsp;event in Japan,&nbsp;but&nbsp;only the&nbsp;fifth Boulder World Cup in&nbsp;the Asian country.&nbsp;<br />&nbsp;<br /><strong>Top Stat:</strong>&nbsp;For every Boulder World Cup competition that has taken place in Japan, there has been at least one Japanese representative on the podium in both genders,&nbsp;however, there has never been a Japanese winner at a men’s Boulder World Cup in Japan. Narasaki&nbsp;Tomoa has&nbsp;won the&nbsp;Boulder World&nbsp;Championship&nbsp;in Hachioji in 2019, but there have been no men’s World Cup wins.<br />&nbsp;<br /><strong>ATHLETES' STATS</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Women's Boulder competitors:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Petra Klinger&nbsp;(SUI):&nbsp;will be her&nbsp;61st World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder –&nbsp;fifth on&nbsp;the&nbsp;all time list for appearances in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Fanny Gibert&nbsp;(FRA):&nbsp;will be her&nbsp;48th World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder –&nbsp;11th on&nbsp;the&nbsp;all time list for appearances in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Nonaka&nbsp;Miho&nbsp;(JPN):&nbsp;will be her&nbsp;45th World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Sol&nbsp;Sa&nbsp;(KOR):&nbsp;will be her&nbsp;44th World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Alannah Yip (CAN):&nbsp;will be her&nbsp;30th World Cup appearance&nbsp;making her the&nbsp;Canadian female record&nbsp;holder.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Men's Boulder competitors:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Jernej Kruder&nbsp;(SLO):&nbsp;will be his&nbsp;82nd World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder –&nbsp;second on&nbsp;the&nbsp;all time list, just one behind&nbsp;Kilian Fischhuber&nbsp;(AUT)&nbsp;who is top&nbsp;with 83 appearances;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Jan Hojer&nbsp;(GER):&nbsp;will be his&nbsp;58th World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder, matching&nbsp;the&nbsp;German record of Jonas Baumann –&nbsp;10th on all time list for appearances in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Kokoro Fujii&nbsp;(JPN):&nbsp;will be his&nbsp;51st World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Jakob Schubert&nbsp;(AUT): will be his&nbsp;50th World Cup appearance in&nbsp;Boulder;</li>
<li data-mce-word-list="1">Alex Khazanov (ISR):&nbsp;will be his&nbsp;41st World Cup appearance&nbsp;making him the&nbsp;Israeli&nbsp;record&nbsp;holder.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>IFSC WORLD CUP PODIUMS IN JAPAN</strong><br />&nbsp;<br />Women's Boulder podiums:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">IFSC World&nbsp;Cup&nbsp;Kazo 2009:<br />G -&nbsp;Noguchi Akiyo (JPN), S -&nbsp;Jain Kim (KOR), B -&nbsp;Anna Stöhr (AUT)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup&nbsp;Kazo 2016:<br />G -&nbsp;Shauna Coxsey (GBR), S -&nbsp;Melissa Le&nbsp;Neve (FRA), B –&nbsp;Nonaka Miho (JPN)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup Hachioji&nbsp;2017:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />G -&nbsp;Janja Garnbret (SLO), S –&nbsp;Noguchi Akiyo (JPN), B -&nbsp;Nonaka Miho (JPN)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup Hachioji&nbsp;2018:<br />G –&nbsp;Noguchi&nbsp;Akiyo&nbsp;(JPN), S –&nbsp;Nonaka Miho (JPN), B -&nbsp;Ekaterina Kipriianova (RUS)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Men's Boulder podiums:<br />&nbsp;<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup&nbsp;Kazo 2009:<br />G -&nbsp;Stéphan Julien (FRA), S -&nbsp;Muraoka&nbsp;Tatsuya, (JPN) B -&nbsp;Rustam Gelmanov (RUS)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup&nbsp;Kazo 2016:<br />G -&nbsp;Rustam Gelmanov (RUS), S -&nbsp;Michael Piccolruaz (ITA), B -&nbsp;Fujii&nbsp;Kokoro&nbsp;(JPN)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup Hachioji&nbsp;2017:<br />G -&nbsp;Aleksei Rubtsov (RUS), S -&nbsp;Narasaki&nbsp;Tomoa&nbsp;(JPN), B -&nbsp;Watabe&nbsp;Keita&nbsp;(JPN)<br />IFSC World&nbsp;Cup Hachioji&nbsp;2018:<br />G -&nbsp;Gabriele Moroni (ITA), S -&nbsp;Narasaki&nbsp;Tomoa&nbsp;(JPN), B -&nbsp;Sugimoto Rei (JPN)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Sport Climbing stat master Paul Higham will be highlighting his top facts and figures throughout the 2023 season for the IFSC. Brit Higham, based in Chamonix, France, is a climbing superfan with a special talent for picking some stand-out stats for the IFSC event calendar.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230419_IFSC_News_Highams_highlights_IFSC_World_Cup_Hachioji_2023.jpg" alt="230419 IFSC News Highams highlights IFSC World Cup Hachioji 2023" width="800" height="534" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nonaka Miho (JPN) competes in Boulder <br />Photo: Lena Drapella / IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 09:46:37 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IFSC DEEPLY SADDENED BY THE TRAGIC LOSS OF CHRISTOPH SCHWEIGER</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/912-ifsc-deeply-saddened-by-the-tragic-loss-of-christoph-schweiger</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/912-ifsc-deeply-saddened-by-the-tragic-loss-of-christoph-schweiger</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230412_IFSC_News_-_IFSC_deeply_saddened_by_the_tragic_loss_of_Christoph_Schweiger_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">It is with great sadness that the IFSC learned of the&nbsp;tragic loss&nbsp;of climber Christoph Schweiger&nbsp;in a road traffic accident&nbsp;at the age of 21.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">From Ingolstadt in Bavaria, Germany, Christoph was a regular on the IFSC World Cup circuit after making his debut at the IFSC World Cup Hachioji in 2018. Mainly focusing on the Boulder discipline, Christoph was part of the German team at the IFSC Youth World Championships competing at three editions between 2017 and 2019. In 2016 Christoph claimed three Boulder medals at the European Youth Cup events with a gold in Graz, Austria and silver in Soure, Portugal and Warsaw, Poland.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">IFSC President Marco Scolaris said: “For someone to lose their life so young in this way is heart-breaking. My thoughts, and everyone’s at the IFSC, are with Christoph’s family, his&nbsp;friends, the Deutscher Alpenverein,&nbsp;and the whole climbing community.”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230412_IFSC_News_-_IFSC_deeply_saddened_by_the_tragic_loss_of_Christoph_Schweiger.jpg" alt="230412 IFSC News IFSC deeply saddened by the tragic loss of Christoph Schweiger" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: Dimitris Tosidis/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 08:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FINAL DAY IN SINGAPORE FOR XIX IFSC GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/909-final-day-in-singapore-for-xix-ifsc-general-assembly</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/909-final-day-in-singapore-for-xix-ifsc-general-assembly</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_Final_day_in_Singapore_for_XIX_IFSC_General_AssemblyPREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">The Mayor of Singapore – Southeast District, Mohd Fahmi Aliman was the guest of honour for the final day of the XIX International Federation of Sport Climbing (IFSC) General Assembly which ended earlier today (1 April) in Singapore. During a short speech, Aliman thanked the IFSC and the delegates for coming to Singapore and highlighted the impact that climbing has had on the southeast Asian country with more than 40 gyms now operating.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Delegates from the 46 National Federations were presented with the IFSC 2022 Annual Report which was introduced by the IFSC President Marco Scolaris. He highlighted some of the achievements of the year including climbing’s introduction to the European Championships in Munich, Germany and the successful IFSC Climbing Summit. He encouraged the delegates to read the report which includes messages from the IFSC leadership, a review of the 2022 IFSC season, the financial reports, and a summary of the work of the National Federations and IFSC staff. A digital version of the 2022 Annual Report is available at&nbsp;<a href="https://reports.ifsc-climbing.org/2022"></a><a href="https://reports.ifsc-climbing.org/2022">https://reports.ifsc-climbing.org/2022</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">IFSC General Director Piero Rebaudengo presented the new IFSC staff structure and the plan for an&nbsp;IFSC subsidiary for the promotion of Sport Climbing through the commercialisation of its events which will be proposed for a vote at the end of 2023. The IFSC Treasurer Pierre You gave some additional insights on the value of a subsidiary before he presented the financial report which was subsequently approved by delegates.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Before the Continental Councils delivered their annual reports, IFSC Secretary General Debra Gawrych presented the Association of Summer Olympic International Federations (ASOIF) Integrity Unit. She highlighted the extra support the new unit can offer the IFSC for the development of its policies before introducing three candidates for the newly reformed IFSC Ethics Commission,&nbsp;USA's Patti Rube, Ethiopian Dagmawit Girmay Berhane and Italian Mario Morelli who were all approved by the delegates.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The afternoon session began with a video presentation from the chair of the IFSC Paraclimbing Commission, Sebastian Depke who introduced a fellow commission member, Sian Spencer, who presented the review and plans for classification as well as rules and equipment for Paraclimbing before President Scolaris mentionedthe&nbsp;potential inclusion of Paraclimbing as an additional sport at LA28.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">IFSC Vice-President Wolfgang Wabel presented a review of the World Cup Series, The World Games, Youth World Championships and European Championships before introducing a video to promote the upcoming 2023 World Championships in Bern, Switzerland. This was followed by the selection of Seoul as the host of the 2025 Climbing World Championships after a presentation from the Korea Alpine Federation (KAF).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As recognition for the performances of their athletes during the 2022 World Cup season, the Team Trophies were given to the representatives of Japan, USA and France.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Delegates received an update on the work of the Sport Department from IFSC Sport Director Maddie Dunn which included the event strategy and the bidding process as well as information regarding the future of Athlete Screening. This was followed by a presentation from IFSC Vice-President Kobinata Toru who provided updates regarding Paris 2024 and the Olympic Qualifier Series that will begin early next year.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A proposal to change the age eligibility from age 16 to 17 for the senior IFSC events, which includes the World Cups and World Championships, from 2025 onwards was put to the delegates with 57% voting in favour.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Olympian and Athletes’ Commission President Shauna Coxsey spoke passionately about the value that athletes give to having positions on the board and representation throughout the IFSC Commissions structure. She also shared the focus of the Athletes’ Commission for 2023, Speed and Boulder formats, athlete health and fairness and inclusion.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The new IFSC Media and Communications Director Fabrizio Rossini delivered his strategy for the future which includes a new user-friendly website and a focus on internal communications with the Federations and a new approach to content which showcases the athletes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The final report of the General Assembly was given by the IFSC Development Director Silvia Verdolini who highlighted the value of the development programmes including the World Climbing Academy, the Women in Sport High Performance Pathway, and the routesetter clinics.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Prior to the closing remarks from the IFSC President, delegates were asked to vote for the hosts of the 2024 and 2025 General Assemblies, which were duly awarded to Santiago in 2024 and Cyprus in 2025 after presentations from Willy Montenegro, President of the Chilean Climbing Federation, and Pavlos Georgiades, President of Cyprus Mountaineering Climbing&nbsp;&amp; Orienteering.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Looking ahead to the rest of 2023, President Scolaris highlighted the European Games in Poland, the Pan American Games in Chile and the Asian Games in China which will include Climbing for the very first time. His final act of the busy two days was to thank the hosts of the General Assembly, all the delegates who actively participated and the IFSC staff for their continued hard work and dedication.</p>
<p><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_Final_day_in_Singapore_for_XIX_IFSC_General_Assembly.jpg" alt="230401 IFSC News Final day in Singapore for XIX IFSC General Assembly" width="800" height="533" /></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 12:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2025 CLIMBING WORLD CHAMPIONSHIPS TO BE HELD IN SEOUL</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/908-2025-climbing-world-championships-to-be-held-in-seoul</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/908-2025-climbing-world-championships-to-be-held-in-seoul</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_2025_Climbing_World_Championships_to_be_held_in_SeoulPREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">The South Korean capital Seoul will host the 2025 Climbing World Championships after the IFSC General Assembly awarded hosting rights to the Korea Alpine Federation (KAF).</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">With a population of around 10 million, the Korean metropolis will host the third World Championships to be held in Asia, and the first in South Korea. The first Asian host of the competition was Qinghai, China in 2009, with&nbsp;Hachioji, Japan becoming the second in 2019.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Seoul made its debut on the IFSC World Cup circuit in 2022 by welcoming the Boulder and Speed disciplines in May, the second stop on the 2022 calendar. The city is also set to host a World Cup event for the second consecutive year at the end of April 2023 before the premier youth event – the Climbing Youth World Championships – takes place in the city from 18 to 27 August 2023.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The 2023 IFSC Climbing and Paraclimbing World Championships are set to take place in the Swiss capital of Bern from 1 to 12 August 2023 and will offer the first qualifying opportunities for the following year’s Olympic Games, where Sport Climbing will award two gold medals per gender: in the new Boulder &amp; Lead format, and in Speed.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_2025_Climbing_World_Championships_to_be_held_in_Seoul.jpg" alt="230401 IFSC News 2025 Climbing World Championships to be held in Seoul" width="800" height="534" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Seoul, South Korea has hosted the IFSC World Cup in 2022 and set to host another in 2023</span>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 07:53:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IFSC CONFIRMS NEW ETHICS COMMISSION WITH ADDITIONS OF RUBE, BERHANE AND MORELLI</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/907-ifsc-expands-ethics-commission-with-addition-of-berhane-and-morelli</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/907-ifsc-expands-ethics-commission-with-addition-of-berhane-and-morelli</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_IFSC_expands_Ethics_Commission_with_addition_of_Berhane_and_MorelliPREV.jpg" /></p><p>The IFSC Member Federations voted to approve three new members to the IFSC Ethics Commission, USA's Patti Rube, Ethiopian Dagmawit Girmay Berhane and Italian Mario Morelli, at the XIX IFSC General Assembly in Singapore.</p>

<p>Rube, Berhane and Morelli were all ratified by the IFSC General Assembly to make up the newly reformed Ethics Commission.</p>
<p>PATTI RUBE</p>
<p>Current Chair of the Board of Directors at the USA Climbing Foundation, and former President of USA Climbing, Harvard Law graduate Rube was chosen for her exemplary knowledge and extensive experience in climbing, ethics and legal matters.</p>
<p>DAGMAWIT GIRMAY BERHANE</p>
<p>Berhane is well-known in Olympic circles, holding many positions in sports organisations at the national, continental, and international levels. She was President of the Ethiopian National Olympic Committee between 2004-2008, and has vast knowledge and experience in international sport, in particular from her work in badminton, including six years as President of the Badminton World Federation (2013-2018).</p>
<p>Since 2013 Berhane has been a member of the International Olympic Committee (IOC), taking roles in the fields of Finance, Auditing and Games Coordination. Her most recent appointment was in 2022 as a&nbsp;member of the IOC Advisory Committee on Human Rights.</p>
<p>MARIO MORELLI</p>
<p>Passing the bar exam in 1998, esteemed sports lawyer Morelli founded Studio Legale Morelli in 2001 with his brother Enzo, to offer legal services in&nbsp;the fields of intellectual property, communications and sports.</p>
<p>Morelli has gained considerable experience in the world of sport&nbsp;on the national and international stage&nbsp;to compliment his wealth of legal knowledge. He has managed&nbsp;Italian team Thunder Dolce Gabbana at the&nbsp;World&nbsp;Boxing&nbsp;Championship and was&nbsp;appointed&nbsp;Chairman of the Board of Directors&nbsp;for&nbsp;the AIBA World Boxing Championships Milan 2009.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/04_APR/230401_IFSC_News_IFSC_expands_Ethics_Commission_with_addition_of_Berhane_and_Morelli.jpg" alt="230401 IFSC News IFSC expands Ethics Commission with addition of Berhane and Morelli" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patti Rube speaks at the XIX IFSC General Assembly © Faizola Nordin/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 04:08:38 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>XIX IFSC GENERAL ASSEMBLY UNDERWAY IN SINGAPORE</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/906-xix-ifsc-general-assembly-underway-in-singapore</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/906-xix-ifsc-general-assembly-underway-in-singapore</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230331_IFSC_News_XIX_IFSC_General_Assembly_underway_in_SingaporePREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">The XIX IFSC General Assembly got underway earlier today (31 March) at the Swissôtel The Stamford in Singapore, with 65 delegates from 46 National Federations making the trip to the southeast Asian country.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><br />On hand to welcome the delegates was IFSC President Marco Scolaris, who thanked the&nbsp;Singapore Sport Climbing and Mountaineering Federation for hosting the annual event during his address and went on to highlight the importance of coming together and shaping the vision and long-term success of the sport.&nbsp;<br /><br />International Olympic Committee (IOC) President Thomas Bach spoke to the attendees via video message, in which he acknowledged the work done by the IFSC in planning for the future and for its excellent preparations for the Olympic Games Paris 2024, specifically referencing the Olympic Qualifier Series (OQS), a new IOC-led Olympic qualification event hosted in compact city centre venues over four days between March and June 2024 that will include four sports – BMX freestyle, breaking, skateboarding, and Sport Climbing.&nbsp;<br /><br />“We are excited to have the&nbsp;IFSC and the Sport Climbing community on board for this innovative festival of sport and culture,” President Bach said. “Bringing sport to where the people are and highlighting the achievements of the athletes on their road to Paris 2024. In doing so you are once again leading by example, and this is something you can all be very, very proud of.”&nbsp;<br /><br />Bach continued: “From the OQS to promoting gender equality, to strengthening clean sport or developing robust safeguarding measures, at the IFSC you are promoting sport and its values in an exemplary way.”&nbsp;To see the full message from President Bach&nbsp;click&nbsp;<a title="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=1c1869a18e&amp;e=ebc07658c0" href="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=1c1869a18e&amp;e=ebc07658c0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ogsc="rgb(0, 0, 0)">here</a>.<br /><br />The General Assembly voted to accept five new National Federations from Iceland, Kosovo, Kuwait, Lebanon, and Morocco, bringing the total number to 99 members. There were also changes in representative bodies in Azerbaijan and name changes for four Federations. Full details of the Member Federations and changes can be found&nbsp;<a title="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=7e27e4c300&amp;e=ebc07658c0" href="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=7e27e4c300&amp;e=ebc07658c0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ogsc="rgb(0, 0, 0)">here</a>.<br /><br />With much of the day taken up with discussions linked to&nbsp;governance and succession planning topics, the National Federations&nbsp;were led through recommendations linked to Board Structure,&nbsp;Continental Roles, Democracy and Term Limits by the IFSC Governance Commission that will be voted on during an extraordinary General Assembly later in the year.<br /><br />Before the end of Day one, the delegates were asked to vote on a proposal to allow current IFSC President Marco Scolaris an opportunity to run for one further term in 2025. The proposal was accepted by the majority with the request for a robust succession plan developed to ensure continuity at the top level of the IFSC. Additional details regarding the vote&nbsp;can be found&nbsp;<a title="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=82ed853325&amp;e=ebc07658c0" href="https://ifsc-climbing.us15.list-manage.com/track/click?u=6196bad354e3ecf21c549d32a&amp;id=82ed853325&amp;e=ebc07658c0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ogsc="rgb(0, 0, 0)">here</a>.<br /><br />The General Assembly will continue tomorrow (1 April) with Finance, Sport, Development and Media among the topics on the agenda.</p>
<p><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230331_IFSC_News_XIX_IFSC_General_Assembly_underway_in_Singapore.jpg" alt="230331 IFSC News XIX IFSC General Assembly underway in Singapore" width="800" height="533" /></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:19:33 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>VOTE OPENS DOOR FOR PRESIDENT SCOLARIS TO RUN IN 2025</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/905-federations-vote-opens-door-for-president-scolaris-to-run-in-2025</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/905-federations-vote-opens-door-for-president-scolaris-to-run-in-2025</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/310323_IFSC_News_Federations_vote_opens_door_for_President_Scolaris_to_run_in_2025_PREV.jpg" /></p><p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">The IFSC General Assembly in Singapore voted for a proposed exception which would allow current President Marco Scolaris to&nbsp;stand again for a&nbsp;final term in the 2025 General Election.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>

<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">Alongside the Presidency vote, Federations requested a succession plan from the IFSC Executive Board that would ensure a smooth transition when new leadership is confirmed.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">The need for an exception was passed with 71% of votes cast.</span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">President Scolaris said: “We are a close family, and we are an open family. Throughout the first day of our General Assembly our Federation representatives have listened, discussed, and more importantly, asked the questions they have needed to make their decisions.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">“Because of this, I know thought and consideration has gone into this vote and it would be my privilege to consider representing our members and carry on in our Olympic journey after 2025.”&nbsp;</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">When the IFSC was founded in 2007, and Scolaris subsequently named President in 2009, the Federation’s long-term goal was to showcase Sport Climbing at the 2028 Games. The IFSC has grown rapidly in a short space of time and surpassed its goal to debut at Tokyo 2020 – two editions earlier than envisaged.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">With the accelerated completion of the Olympic objectives, the goals and needs of the IFSC have shifted to ensure a smooth transition from a pandemic effected Games, to an additional sport at Paris 2024, to a programme sport in Los Angeles.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span></p>
<p class="paragraph" style="text-align: justify;"><span class="normaltextrun"><span lang="EN-GB">Success and exponential growth have again been recognised as a factor among stakeholders leading to the decision for the exception.</span></span><span class="eop"><span lang="EN-GB"></span></span><span lang="EN-GB"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/310323_IFSC_News_Federations_vote_opens_door_for_President_Scolaris_to_run_in_2025.jpg" alt="310323 IFSC News Federations vote opens door for President Scolaris to run in 2025" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">President addressing delegates at the 2023 General Assembly © Faizola Nordin/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 10:40:39 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IFSC WITHIN TOUCHING DISTANCE OF MEMBER FEDERATIONS CENTURY</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/904-ifsc-within-touching-distance-of-member-federations-century</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/904-ifsc-within-touching-distance-of-member-federations-century</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/310323_IFSC_IFSC_within_touching_distance_of_Member_Federations_century_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The IFSC welcomed five new Member Federations to its family at the XIX General Assembly in Singapore, taking the total to 99 from across the globe.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The addition of Iceland, Kosovo, Kuwait, Lebanon and Morocco means that the International Federation is just shy of the 100 mark, representing a steady increase from the 57 founding members in 2007.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">All application requests to join the IFSC were ratified by the General Assembly. In addition, the GA also approved a number of country representation and organisational name changes, while confirming that it would waive the annual fees once again for the Ukrainian Mountaineering and Climbing Federation (UMCF).</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The 2023 admissions are:</span>&nbsp;<br />&nbsp;<br /><span data-contrast="auto">Iceland – represented by the Icelandic Climbing Association (ICA/Kí);</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&nbsp;<br /></span><span data-contrast="auto">Kosovo– represented by the Kosovo Mountaineering and Sport Climbing Federation (KMSCF);</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&nbsp;<br /></span><span data-contrast="auto">Kuwait – represented by the Kuwait Climbing Committee (KCC);</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&nbsp;<br /></span><span data-contrast="auto">Lebanon– represented by the Lebanese Federation of Sport Climbing and Mountaineering (LFSCM); and</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&nbsp;<br /></span><span data-contrast="auto">Morocco– represented by the Royal Moroccan Federation of Ski and Mountain Sports (FRMSSM).</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Azerbaijan now has a new representative body, with the Azerbaijan Mountaineering Federation (AMF) being approved to take over the promotion and development of climbing in the country from the Air and Extreme Sports Federation of Azerbaijan (AESFA), which has subsequently had its membership terminated.&nbsp;</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The Member Federation of the Philippines was confirmed as a Full Member, having previously been recognised as a Continental Member. The representative body also changed its name to Pilipinas Climbing, having previously been known as the Sport Climbing Association of the Philippines (SCAPI).</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">There were also name changes for the federations of Portugal and Venezuela. Portugal is now represented by Federação Promotora de Escalada de Competição – having previously been Federação Promotora de Montanhismo e Escalada – and Venezuela is now represented by Federación Venezolana de Escalada Deportiva (FEVED) – previously known as Federación Venezolana de Montañismo y Escalada (FEVME).</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">New Caledonia’s membership was terminated on the request of the former Observer Membership body, the Comité Régional de la Montagne et de l’Escalade de la Nouvelle Calédonie, as it will now be governed by the Fédération Française de la Montagne et de l’Escalade (FFME).</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">It was also announced that the 2023 membership fees for the Ukrainian Mountaineering and Climbing Federation will once again be waived.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/310323_IFSC_IFSC_within_touching_distance_of_Member_Federations_century.jpg" alt="310323 IFSC IFSC within touching distance of Member Federations century" width="800" height="534" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Leslie Romero of Venezuela competes in Boulder&nbsp;© Daniel Gajda/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:16:29 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NATIONAL FEDERATIONS ATTEND IFSC WORKSHOPS IN SINGAPORE</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/903-national-federations-attend-ifsc-workshops-in-singapore</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/903-national-federations-attend-ifsc-workshops-in-singapore</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/300323_IFSC_News_national-federations-attend-ifsc-workshops-in-singaporePREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">In the lead-up to the XIX IFSC General Assembly in Singapore, delegates from the world Climbing family attended a trio of workshops aimed at providing them with key information and best practices that they can take back and apply at the local and national levels.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Held at the Swissôtel The Stamford, the workshops featured a number of presentations and roundtable discussions led by top-level presenters from the world of sport and health.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">With Climbing still new to the Olympic family, Joop Alberda, the gold-medal winning coach of the Netherlands men’s Olympic volleyball team, walked the delegates through what it takes to be in the Olympic environment and how best to assist athletes and Federations on the Olympic path.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Boasting an extensive CV in coaching and sports administration inside the Olympic Movement, Alberda broke down his vast experience in athletics, swimming, rowing, volleyball, cycling and football in an easy-to-follow journey through the Olympic lifecycle.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Alberda conceptualised the journey of Climbing in the Olympics as a journey with stops along the way. He provided a recap of Tokyo 2020, where Climbing made its Olympic debut, before looking ahead to Paris 2024, which he said will give Sport Climbing a much more realistic Olympic experience than at Tokyo 2020, which was held during the coronavirus pandemic and featured numerous restrictions.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Focusing more on National Federations, Alberda worked through the key components of high-performance sport and outlined the values involved before focusing attention on potential future changes that may impact them.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">With new Federations forming around the world and others expanding, Alberda took time to introduce high-performance culture and offered points on how it can be created within organisations.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Dr Margo Mountjoy, a sport medicine doctor, scientist and professor with experience at the Olympic Games and Youth Olympic Games, discussed her expertise in </span><span data-contrast="auto">relative energy deficiency in sport</span><span data-contrast="auto"> (RED-S) </span><span data-contrast="auto">while presenting the most common </span><span data-contrast="auto">signs and symptoms to help raise awareness.</span><span data-contrast="auto"> Mountjoy also </span><span data-contrast="auto">updated the participants on the latest outcomes from the IOC RED-S consensus  statement.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Maria Stefania Ionel&nbsp;</span><span data-contrast="auto">brought the RED-S workshop to a close with a "</span><span data-contrast="auto">Consensus Statement on </span><span data-contrast="auto">​</span><span data-contrast="auto">Eating Disorders in Climbing"</span><span data-contrast="auto">. Ionel is a </span><span data-contrast="auto">Clinical &amp; Sport Psychologist who</span><span data-contrast="auto"> represents a group of nine </span><span data-contrast="auto">psychologists </span><span data-contrast="auto">and the </span><span data-contrast="auto">International Association of Psychologists in Climbing. After discussing </span><span data-contrast="auto">the </span><span data-contrast="auto">signs and symptoms of eating disorders, she finished her presentation with ways to limit </span><span data-contrast="auto">r</span><span data-contrast="auto">isk, increase protection and better manage eating disorders in sport.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Bringing the mental health of athletes into focus, </span><span data-contrast="none">Sam Parfitt, Founder and CEO of </span><a href="https://www.thetrueathleteproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none"><span data-ccp-charstyle="Hyperlink">The True Athlete Project</span><span data-ccp-charstyle="Hyperlink"> (</span><span data-ccp-charstyle="Hyperlink">TAP)</span></span></a><span data-contrast="none">&nbsp;-</span><span data-contrast="auto"> a charity in Great Britain and USA with the aim of building a more compassionate world through sport – addressed delegates.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;335551550&quot;:0,&quot;335551620&quot;:0}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Taking attendees on another journey, this time through TAP and his own personal experiences, Parfitt looked at the challenges within Climbing and the importance of legacy and what the Federations may want to leave behind.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;335551550&quot;:0,&quot;335551620&quot;:0}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">As a group there were reflections and memories from the Federations about Climbing before feedback about those experiences. The next step in the workshop was how those experiences could potentially change for the better for&nbsp;future generations. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;335551550&quot;:0,&quot;335551620&quot;:0}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">Parfitt welcomed Athletes' Commission representatives Shauna Coxsey and Sean McColl to his session to give a first-hand elite perspective and add further insight from the top end of the sport.&nbsp;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;335551550&quot;:0,&quot;335551620&quot;:0}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">General Assembly hosts Singapore Sport Climbing and Mountaineering Federation brought Dominik Pandurević and&nbsp;Dr. Klaus Hochradel to present a study they have been working on in conjunction with the federation and the </span><span data-contrast="auto">National Youth Sports Institute -&nbsp;Singapore.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The study, titled </span><span data-contrast="auto">‘</span><span data-contrast="auto">Introduction of a Method for an Automated Motion Capturing System for Speed Climbing’, is a joint venture that looks at the mechanics and movement of Speed climbers through video analysis and data.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span data-contrast="auto">The XIX IFSC General Assembly will continue in Singapore with two days of meetings at Swissôtel The Stamford on 31 March and 1 April.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/300323_IFSC_News_national-federations-attend-ifsc-workshops-in-singapore.jpg" alt="300323 IFSC News national federations attend ifsc workshops in singapore" width="800" height="533" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Joop Alberda hosting a workshop in Singapore © Faizola Nordin/IFSC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:40:10 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>WORLD CLIMBING ACADEMY HOLDS PAIR OF ROUTESETTERS’ CLINICS IN LITHUANIA AND GREECE</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/901-world-climbing-academy-holds-pair-of-routesetters-clinics-in-lithuania-and-greece</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/901-world-climbing-academy-holds-pair-of-routesetters-clinics-in-lithuania-and-greece</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230329_IFSC_News_-_World_Climbing_Academy_holds_pair_of_Routesetters_Clinics_in_Lithuania_and_Greece_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">Launched in November 2022, in collaboration with World Academy of Sport, World Climbing Academy commenced its activities with the <a href="https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/892-ibarra-ecuador-hosts-world-climbing-academy-pilot-course">first IFSC Routesetters’ Clinic</a> – held in Ibarra, Ecuador – in early December.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">The same format was replicated twice at the beginning of 2023, with two more Clinics organised in Kaunas, Lithuania, from 13 to 16 February; and Athens, Greece, from 2 to 5 March.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The IFSC Routesetters’ Clinic in Kaunas was conducted by IFSC Routesetter Tonde Katyio and saw the participation of 12 trainees – including five women.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230329_IFSC_News_-_World_Climbing_Academy_holds_pair_of_Routesetters_Clinics_in_Lithuania_and_Greece_01.jpg" alt="230329 IFSC News World Climbing Academy holds pair of Routesetters Clinics in Lithuania and Greece 01" width="800" height="600" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Participants of the IFSC Routesetters' Clinic in Kaunas</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: LLSF</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“</em><em>Many questions were asked and so many relevant discussions happened during the 4 days route setters' training with Tonde Katyio</em><em>,”</em> said participant Aušrinė Balkaitytė. <em>“</em><em>From practical tips and tricks to philosophical approaches. From 1</em><em>2</em><em> strangers to getting to know each other at least a tiny bit better. And we strongly believe that something beautiful or at least interesting will grow out of this experience in the future!</em><em>”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“</em><em>The workshop experience was undoubtedly one of the best things that happened </em><em>to the</em><em> Lithuanian </em><em>C</em><em>limbing community </em><em>in</em><em> a long time</em><em>,”</em> added Dainius Saržickas. <em>“</em><em>For </em><em>a </em><em>beginner routesetter </em><em>like</em><em> me, Tonde gave me motivation, methods and different understanding of our craft. I would definitely like to experience something similar in my future as routesetter.</em><em>”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Clinic organised in Athens featured the same training team that conducted the course in Ibarra – Matthias Woitzuk and Mauro Schwatszta – and saw the participation of a group of athletes from the Greek national team.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t0Otz1KWI9I" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The two Routesetters’ Clinics were structured around 10 key evaluation points: safety, teamwork, communication, time management, setting methodology, setting craft, creativity, forerunning and athletic empathy, self-evaluation as a climber, and work ethic. attitudeand saw the participation of 12 trainees.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Each participant left their Clinic with a goal, or a task to be performed in the following weeks and months – like setting for a mock event, or at National level, creating a specific route or problem, or simply upgrading their level of setting. Follow-up interviews with the respective trainers will be scheduled to check in on the trainees’ progress.</p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 09:39:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IFSC CLIMBS UP FIVE PLACES IN LATEST LEAGUE TABLE REPORT BY REDTORCH</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/900-ifsc-climbs-up-five-places-in-latest-league-table-report-by-redtorch</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/900-ifsc-climbs-up-five-places-in-latest-league-table-report-by-redtorch</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230315_IFSC_News_-_IFSC_climbs_up_five_places_in_latest_League_Table_report_by_Redtorch_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">London-based research, digital, and creative agency <a href="https://redtorch.sport/">Redtorch</a> published today the latest edition of its yearly report – League Table 2023 – analysing the digital performance of every Olympic International Federation across Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, YouTube, and TikTok.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">After placing in 22<sup>nd</sup> position in the 2022 report, the International Federation of Sport Climbing (IFSC) moved up five places and placed 17<sup>th</sup> in 2023 – the sixth best results among the 40 organisations.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The report also highlights the fact that the IFSC recorded the second highest growth rate on Facebook – +49% – and includes an interview with IFSC Head of Digital Marco Vettoretti.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The full report is available here: <a href="https://redtorch.sport/sportonsocial-league-table-2023/"></a><a href="https://redtorch.sport/sportonsocial-league-table-2023/">https://redtorch.sport/sportonsocial-league-table-2023/</a></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:55:43 +0100</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PARIS 2024 VENUES TO BE LINKED BY 55 KMS OF NEW CYCLE LANES</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/898-paris-2024-venues-to-be-linked-by-55kms-of-new-cycle-lanes</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/898-paris-2024-venues-to-be-linked-by-55kms-of-new-cycle-lanes</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/Placeholders/IFSC_News_-_Paris_placeholder_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">Climbing fans will be able to cycle from the centre of Paris to Seine-Saint-Denis, the home of the Sport Climbing venue, to catch a glimpse of the stars of our sport in Olympic action as 55-kilometres of new bike lanes are set to be completed by July 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Scheduled for 26 July to 11 August, Paris 2024 will be Sport Climbing’s second outing at an Olympic Games following a hugely successful debut at Tokyo 2020 with competition taking place at the Le Bourget Climbing venue situated in the north-eastern suburb of the city – an area known for its young population.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The purpose-built venue and indoor Climbing facilities in Seine-Saint-Denis will provide a lasting legacy after the Games which goes hand in hand with Paris Mayor Anne Hidalgo’s vision for the additional bike lanes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Finished in time for next summer’s sporting showpiece, the French capital city announced&nbsp;25 kilometres of new ‘Olympilanes’ will span the Seine-Saint-Denis area in addition to the 30 kilometres of cycling routes in Paris already in place or is about to be completed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">IFSC President Marco Scolaris said: “We can’t wait to see the final plan of the cycle lane network and we would be delighted to ride from Paris city centre to our venue, together with our athletes.”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230309_IFSC_News_Paris_2024_venues_to_be_linked_by_55kms_of_new_cycle_lanes.jpg" alt="230309 IFSC News Paris 2024 venues to be linked by 55kms of new cycle lanes" /><br />Seine-Saint-Denis will be linked to the centre of Paris by July 2024</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 08:54:32 +0100</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CLIMBING COACHES FROM SINGAPORE, GREECE, AND THE USA PARTICIPATED IN THE RESIDENCY PHASE OF THE WISH PROGRAMME</title>
			<link>https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/897-climbing-coaches-from-singapore-greece-and-the-usa-participated-in-the-residency-phase-of-the-wish-programme</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ifsc-climbing.org/index.php/news/897-climbing-coaches-from-singapore-greece-and-the-usa-participated-in-the-residency-phase-of-the-wish-programme</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230308_IFSC_News_-_Climbing_coaches_from_Greece_Singapore_and_the_USA_participated_in_the_residency_phase_of_the_WISH_programme_PREV.jpg" /></p><p style="text-align: justify;">From 20 to 24 February, a group of female coaches that included three Sport Climbing representatives gathered at the Institute of Sport at the University of Hertfordshire, Great Britain, for the five days of residency that enhanced their participation in the Women in Sport High Performance Pathway (WISH) programme.</p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Stella Kerasidou of Greece, Beatrix Chong of Singapore, and Meghan McDonald of the USA were selected by the IFSC, to be part of the group of 97 coaches from 53 countries and 17 sports that have enrolled in the programme.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Supported by Olympic Solidarity funding, WISH is a four-year programme designed to equip around 100 women to coach at elite levels by 2024, helping them develop their leadership skills, confidence and careers. Coaches also benefit from one-to-one leadership mentoring, plus ongoing support from a sport-specific mentor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“</em><em>It </em><em>was</em><em> a great honour getting selected as </em><em>one</em><em> of the </em><em>three coaches</em><em> to represent Sport Climbing </em><em>in the</em><em> WISH programme</em><em>,”</em> said Chong. <em>“I had the chance</em><em> of sharing session with women from other sports and nationalities</em><em>, and the</em> <em>f</em><em>acilitator c</em><em>ame</em><em> up with a variety of activities to help bring out the leadership and teamwork in us</em><em>,</em> <em>a</em><em>ssisting us to acknowledge our strength and weakness. </em><em>I am very much l</em><em>ooking forward to seeing how much more I can grow as a coach after this program</em><em>!”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Kerasidou said: <em>“I really liked </em><em>that I came close with female coaches from all around the world and s</em><em>aw</em><em> that they have the same concerns as me</em><em>,</em><em> and they face the same problems. So it makes me feel that it's not something that I'm doing wrong</em><em>,</em><em> but that all these difficulties </em><em>really </em><em>exist. </em><em>I</em><em> like how we are coming closer, and we </em><em>are </em><em>learn</em><em>ing</em><em> from each other</em><em>’s</em><em> experiences. And</em> <em>the tasks we </em><em>did </em><em>in the program</em><em>me</em><em> help</em><em>ed</em><em> us to understand better the different situations and from different perspectives.</em><em>”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>“It’s been a wonderful opportunity. I was thrilled to be in that cohort of amazingly talented female coaches and leaders. There’s so much wisdom, experience, and kindness! I’m eager to expand my breadth of knowledge and to push my capacity as a coach and a leader,”</em> said McDonald.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="https://cdn.ifsc-climbing.org/images/News/2023/03_MAR/230308_IFSC_News_-_Climbing_coaches_from_Greece_Singapore_and_the_USA_participated_in_the_residency_phase_of_the_WISH_programme.jpg" alt="230308 IFSC News Climbing coaches from Greece Singapore and the USA participated in the residency phase of the WISH programme" width="800" height="534" /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Participants of the third cohort of the WISH programme</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photo: IOC</span></p>]]></description>
			<category>News</category>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 15:03:50 +0100</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
